

Bogdan Alexandrescu

Bogdan is a technology expert and industry leader. A successful entrepreneur with previous start-ups in technology, fintech, and business consulting. Member of the Bitcoin Foundation and active investor and advisor in the blockchain ecosystem. Tech Lead at Apple Inc, with a focus on large-scale Machine Learning & Al infrastructure projects. Previously Tech Lead for Twitter Ads

bogdan@alexandrescu.io http://www.linkedin.com/in/alexandrescu

(415) 660-8886 San Francisco, CA

Experience

Apple (Cupertino, CA)

Engineering Manager, 2018 - Present



Tech Lead Sr. SWE, 2017 - 2018

Architect, build and support Big Data, Machine Learning and Al pipelines at scale for the
real-time analysis of Apple MAPS data and services. Lead an org-wide standardization and
integration effort meant to streamline and improve the ongoing evaluation of MAPS data
and service releases.

Senior SRE, 2016 - 2017

 Build and support distributed and highly available compute platforms. Productionalize and automate big data ingestion and processing pipelines. Software product arhitecture reviews and disaster recovery strategies, tooling and monitoring. Agile sprint planning and training.

Twitter (San Francisco, CA)



Software Engineer - Tech Lead, Twitter Ads, 2015 - 2016

Design and implement client facing features and advertising formats for twitter.com in
order to drive up engagements and increase overall product quality and advertising
revenue. Coordinating tasks and syncronizing with other leads, PMs and designers on
technical requirements, UX/UI designs & release dates as well as supporting and
mentoring teammates.

Software Engineer, Infrastructure Services, 2014 - 2015

• Lead the design and development of an end-to-end capacity planning and management solution. Other projects involved building reliable and highly available automation software in distributed environments (Mesos, Hadoop) to handle an end-to-end strategy for fleet analytics, provisioning, allocation and infrastructure operations.

UC Davis (Davis, CA)



Research - Assistant Specialist, 2012 - 2016

Develop and maintain a MySQL database driven Web Applications and UC Davis AWS
 Server for collecting and administrating the research data needed for the Federal Grant
 (USDA) funded projects.

AV Franchise Consulting (Bucharest, RO)



Founder & CTO, 2009 - 2011

• Lead the technology efforts of one of the biggest franchise consulting businesses in Romania. Provided integration (website, In house CRM software) for the company's database of 6000 clients/partners management. Built the web directory with the highest traffic in this business segment in Romania.



Bogdan Alexandrescu

Bogdan is a technology expert and industry leader. A successful entrepreneur with previous start-ups in technology, fintech, and business consulting. Member of the Bitcoin Foundation and active investor and advisor in the blockchain ecosystem. Tech Lead at Apple Inc, with a focus on large-scale Machine Learning & Al infrastructure projects. Previously Tech Lead for Twitter Ads

bogdan@alexandrescu.io http://www.linkedin.com/in/alexandrescu

(415) 660-8886 San Francisco, CA

Webstyle Solutions (Bucharest, RO)



Founder & Team Lead, 2007 - 2011

 Provided leadership, architectural, and process direction for the following services and products: web development, web hosting, domain registry, IT outsourcing and website maintenance. Lead the efforts in the integration of electronic payment systems with Authorize.net, PayPal, Mobilpay and Gecad.

Education

Harvard Business School

HBX CORe, 2016-2017

Graduated with Honors

University of California, Davis

MS, Computer Science, 2012 - 2014

GPA: 3.85/4.0

Cibernetics, Statistics & CS - ASE Bucharest

BS, Computer Science, 2004 - 2008

GPA: 3.65/4.0

Skills

- Software Engineering: Golang, Python, Scala, Java, Solidity, PHP, Bash/Shell, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Flight.js, AngularJS, ReactJS, Typescript, Jasmine, SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle), Non-SQL (MongoDB, Redis, Manhattan, Elastic Search, Solr, Cassandra), Distributed Computing (Mesos/Maraton/Aurora, Kubernetes, Hadoop/HDFS, Hive, Spark, Heroku, AWS Stack, Zookeeper), Blockchain Technology, Jenkins, Artifactory, Druid/Superset, Tableau, Kibana
- System Engineering: Docker, VMWare, Citrix Netscaler, CloudFlare, Akamai, Nginx+, HAProxy, DNS, Kickstart, Switch and Network configuration, Firewalls, Puppet, Chef, Tracing, Splunk, ELK Stack, Zipkin, Zabbix, InfluxDB/Grafana
- Information Security: Intrusion Detection, PEN Testing, Cryptography
- Leadership: Serial entrepreneur and advisor. Leading teams of engineers working on software products and large scale infrastructure projects
- **Project Management**: Scrum and Agile Metodology project management, OKR and Roadmap Planning
- Languages: Fluent speaker of English, Italian, Romanian and beginner level in French, Spanish & Mandarin.

Leadership Affiliations

- Bitcoin Foundation, Active Member (2018 Present)
- Blockchain Investors Consortium, Active Member (2017 Present)
- Graduate Student Association, UC DAVIS, Computer Science Representative (2012-2013)
- Mensa, Active Member (2011 Present)
- Rotaract (Rotary International), President 2012 (2008 2012)
- Business Club & VIPRomania, Active Member (2004-2008)





